Guide to the Communications Workers of America, District 1 Records WAG.117
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Bargaining Files, 1966-1989
  - Local 1109 (American Teleconnect Corp., Mt. Vernon, NY) I, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Local 1109 (American Teleconnect Corp., Pelham, NY) II, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Local 1109 (Brookville Communications, New York, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Local 1109 (Centennial Telephone Contractors, Inc., Caldwell, NJ), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Local 1109 (Communications Contracting Inc., Whitestone, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Local 1109 (Communications Contractors Group, Inc.), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Local 1109 (Communix, Harriman, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Local 1109 (Connecticut Aerosol, Inc., Milford, CT), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Local 1109 (Coradian Acquisitions Corp., New York, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Local 1109 (DPT Telecommunications), undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Local 1109 (ETCO Communications, Inc., Amityville, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Local 1109 (GHC Inc., Union, NJ), undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Local 1109 (Holgrath Corp., Cheshire, CT) I, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Local 1109 (Holgrath Corp., Cheshire, CT) II, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Local 1109 (K-W Communications, Newburgh, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Local 1109 (Lorna Communications, New York, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Local 1109 (Nassau-Suffolk Interconnect, Inc., East Moriches, NY) I, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Local 1109 (Nassau-Suffolk Interconnect, Inc., East Moriches, NY) II, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Local 1109 (Network Installations), undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Local 1109 (Northeastern Telephone Co., Milford, CT), undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Local 1109 (Northern Telecom Systems, Bloomfield, NJ), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Local 1109 (Reliable Interconnect, Inc., Uniondale, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Local 1109 (Seal, Inc., Naugatuck, CT), undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Local 1109 (Tel-a-ply Communications Inc., New York, NY), undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Local 1109 (Telcom Plus of NYC, Inc., New York, NY: formerly Triboro Telephone Co.), undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Local 1109 (Telecommunications Systems, Inc., Rye, NY) I, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Local 1109 (Telecommunications Systems, Inc., Rye, NY) II, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Local 1109 (Teleprompter Corporation), undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Local 1109 (Tel-Span Corp., Long Island City, NY) I, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Local 1109 (Tel-Span Corp., Long Island City, NY) II, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Local 1109 (Triboro Communications Corp., Brooklyn, NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Local 1109 (United Cable Television Corp. of CT, Plainville, CT), undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Local 1109 (United Technologies Communications Corp., New York, NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Local 1109 (Volt Business Comm. Division, New York NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Local 1111 (Arnot Ogden Memorial Hospital), undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Local 1111 (City School District of Elmira, NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Local 1111 (E.E. Root and Son, Inc.), undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Local 1111 (Iroquois Telephone Corp.; Alfred, Dryden, Cato, NY) I, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Local 1111 (Iroquois Telephone Corp.; Alfred, Dryden, Cato, NY) II, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Local 1111 (Iroquois Telephone Corp. and Western Counties Telephone Co.), undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Local 1111 (Empire Telephone Corp.), undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Local 1111 (Nor East Plastic, Inc.), undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Local 1111 (North Penn Telephone Co., c/o Empire Telephone Corp.), undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Local 1111 (Southern Tioga School District), undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Local 1111 (Teleprompter Electronics Corp., New York, NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Local 1111 (Town of Chemung, NY, Highway Department), undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Local 1115 (Chautauqua and Erie Tel), 1973-1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Local 1120 (NY, KAR-TEL Systems of NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Local 1122 (Buffalo Red Cross, Buffalo, NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Local 1122 (Comax Telcom), 1972-1989 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Local 1122 (Crisis Services, Erie Co., NY), undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Local 1122 (Phone World, Inc.), undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Local 1122 (Sheridan Broadcasting Corp., WUFO Radio Station, Buffalo, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Local 1122 (Sinclair Radio Laboratories, Inc., Tonawanda, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Local 1122 (Visiting Nursing Association of, Inc., Buffalo, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Local 1123 (American Red Cross Regional Blood Services, Syracuse and Onandaga Co.'s, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Local 1123 (SEIU-Clerical), undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Local 1126 (Harron Communications, formerly Central New York Cable, Inc., Utica, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Local 1127 (Native Textiles, Glens Falls, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Local 1141 (New York State Nurses Association, Albany, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Local 1141 (NYS Teachers Association, Albany, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Local 1141 (NYS United Teachers, Albany, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Local 1141 (United University Professions, Inc., Albany, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Local 1162 (Western Counties Telephone Corp., Corfu, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Local 1170 (Rochester Telephone) I, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Local 1170 (Rochester Telephone) II, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Local 1170 (Town Board, Greece, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Local 1172 (American Cable and Radio), undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Local 1172 (ITT Communications), 1970-1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Local 1175 (RCA Service Co., Camden, NJ), undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Local 1177 (Western Union Telegraph Co., New York, NY) I, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Local 1177 (Western Union Telegraph Co., New York, NY) II, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Local 1179 (ITT World Communications, Inc., New York, NY), undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Local 1180 (City of New York) I, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Local 1180 (City of New York) II, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Local 1180 (City of New York) III, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Local 1180 (NYC Transit Authority), undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Local 1180 (State of New York, Unified Court System), undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Local 1181 (Associate Traffic Enforcement Agents, New York, NY), undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Local 1182 (NYC Traffic Control Agents), undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Local 1183 (NYC Board of Elections), 1970-1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Local 1183 (NYC Board of Elections), 1980-1985 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Local 1185 (Air India, New York, NY), undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Local 1187 (Ocean Co., NJ, Board of Social Services) I, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Local 1187 (Ocean Co., NJ, Board of Social Services) II, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Local 1211 (Warner Cable of Eastern Mass.), undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Local 1270 (Philips Medical Systems, Shelton, CT) I, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Local 1270 (Philips Medical Systems, Shelton, CT) II, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Local 1271 (Holgrath Corp., Cheshire, CT), undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Local 1272 (American Installation and Maintenance, Inc., Fairfield, NJ), undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Local 1272 (Interconnect Telephone Service, Inc., New York, NY), undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Local 1272 (Teleprompter County Cable TV Corp., Mt. Vernon, NY), undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Local 1272 (The Star - World News Corp., New York, NY), undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Local 1272 (The Star - News Group Publications, formerly World News Corp., New York, NY), undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Local 1273 (Fluids Control Division of LFE Corp., a.k.a. Eastern Industries, Hamden, CT) I, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Local 1273 (Fluids Control Division of LFE Corp., a.k.a. Eastern Industries, Hamden, CT) II, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Local 1280 (City of Meriden, CT) I, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Local 1280 (City of Meriden, CT) II, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Local 1280 (East Shore District Health Department, Branford, CT), undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Local 1295 (South Central Connecticut Regional Emergency Medical Communications Systems, New Haven, CT), undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Local 1295 (Tri-District Association, West Haven, CT) I, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Local 1295 (Tri-District Association, West Haven, CT) II, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Local 1301 (City of Boston Employees Credit Union, Boston, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Local 1301, 1302, 1303 (New England Telephone and Telegraph Co., Boston, MA) I, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Local 1301, 1302, 1303 (New England Telephone and Telegraph Co., Boston, MA) II, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Local 1302 (Boston College, Boston, MA) I, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Local 1302 (Boston College, Boston, MA) II, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Local 1302 (City of Boston Employees Credit Union), undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Local 1302 (New England Telephone and Telegraph Co., Boston, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Local 1355 (Concord-Carlisle Regional District School Committee, Concord, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Local 1355 (Electrical Light Department of the Town of Littleton, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Local 1355 (TEC/TSC, Chelsea, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Local 1365 (Salisbury Water Supply Co.), undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Local 1365 (Western Electric Co., Inc., Merrimack Valley Works, Merrimack Valley, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Local 1370 (FL Surprenant Wire and Cable Co., Inc., Clinton, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Local 1371 (Hampden Automotive Co., Roxbury, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Local 1372 (Niles Co., Boston, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Local 1372 (Tremont on the Common Management Corp., Boston, MA a.k.a. First Realty Management Corp.), undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Local 1372 (Westbrook Village, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Local 1373 (Warner Amex Cable Communications Inc., Medford, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Local 1374 (Seth Thomas Division, General Time Corp., Fitchburg, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Local 1380 (Boxborough, MA Police Unit), undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Local 1380 (Carlisle, MA Police Unit), undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Local 1380 (Concord, MA Police Unit), undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Local 1380 (Lincoln, MA), undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Local 1380 (Littleton, MA Dispatcher Unit), undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Local 1380 (Littleton, MA Police Unit), undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Local 1380 (Littleton, MA, Water Department), undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Local 1380 (Shirley, MA Police Unit), undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Local 1380 (Stow, MA Dispatchers Unit), undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Local 1380 (Stow, MA Police Unit), undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Local 1400 (New England Telephone and Telegraph Co., Boston, MA), undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Municipal Labor Committee, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - NJ Bell (Traffic and Commercial Bargaining), 1968-1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - NJ Bell (Traffic and Commercial Bargaining), 1973-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - NJ Tel (Traffic and Commercial Bargaining), 1972-1977 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - NY Tel and Empire City Subway: Stipulation, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining I, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining II, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining, 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining (NLRB Case), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - NY Tel: Bargaining (Selection of Committee), 1968 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - NT Tel: Bargaining (Strike Vote), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Western Electric – Bargaining, 1967-1971 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Western Electric – Bargaining, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Western Electric – Bargaining, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Western Electric – Bargaining, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Western Union – Bargaining, 1972-1979 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Series III: Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 9 websites in 9 archived websites.
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains websites created by District 1 of the Communications Workers of America and its locals. Websites mostly are focused on bargaining and strike campaigns within the union; news from members and the union; political activism; and safe staffing implementation at hospitals and nursing homes.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  In 2020, accruals were increased to monthly.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://district1.cwa-union.org/ and https://cwad1.org/in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Arrangement
  Arranged by date of crawl.
  - Communications Workers of America, District 1
    Scope and Contents
    The earliest crawl of the Communications Workers of America, District 1 dates back to 2007 and focused mostly on news from the union, the CWA convention, and District 1's involvement in the CWA's Committee on Political Education, and the campaign to stop the sale of Verizon in Vermont, Maine, and New Hampshire. Captures from 2009 and 2010 focus on bargaining updates with AT&T Mobility; healthcare reform; layoffs at Verizon; and a campaign against E-Z Pass which refused to acknowledge unionized workers at one of their call centers. In late 2010, the website underwent a redesign highlighting news from District 1; leadership; photos and videos from conventions and rallies; bargaining updates; and political activism and endorsements. From 2010-2016, District 1 focused on campaigns related to the sale of T-Mobile; unionization of agents at Piedmont Airlines; E-Z Pass workers in Staten Island; the New Jersey chapter; bargaining with Verizon; Hurricane Sandy Relief Fund; increased staffing for healthcare workers in hospitals and nursing homes; the CWA Joe Beirne Foundation; and the Take On Wall Street campaign to work on reforms beyond the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform Act. In circa 2016-2017, the website was redesigned again. From 2016-2020, the website had a a focus on member benefits; bargaining with AT&T, AT&T Mobility, Verizon, and Catholic Health; CWA Strong national plan; videos and photos from rallies; press releases and other news; legislative-political coordinators; political endorsements; and COVID-19 resources.
    In 2021, the union established a new domain and underwent a redesign. The new website contains news and press releases; their legislative agenda; political endorsements in New York and New Jersey; federal political action efforts; mobilization and bargaining efforts at Verizon, AT&T Mobility, and Catholic Health; COVID-19 pandemic updates and vaccine information; petitions; and the Red on Thursdays campaign.
    District 1's web presence also includes the Safe Staffing website on implementing safe levels of healthcare workers to patients ratios at hospitals and nursing homes and the New Jersey unit website.
  - Catholic Health Workers United
    Historical Note
    Catholic Health Workers United is the organizing and strike website for the Communication Workers of America District 1 Local 1133 related to the bargaining and strike in 2022. Bargaining with the Catholic Health began in 2021 and the strike began on October 1, 2021. They called for safe staffing levels, wage increases, preserving retirement benefits, and keeping healthcare costs low. On November 4, they agreed on a contract.
  - Kaleida Health Workers United
    Kaleida Health Workers United is the bargaining website for members of the Communications Workers of America (CWA) Local 1168 (part of CWA District 1) and 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East (1199SEIU). The local represents registered nurses, nurse practitioners, dietary workers, personal care attendants, professionals, technicians, service and maintenance workers at Kaleida Health hospitals and nursing homes in Western New York. Their contract expired in May 2022.
  - Bird Union
    The Bird Union, formerly Audubon for All, is a local union of the Communications Workers of America, that represents full-time and part-time employees of the National Audubon Society. The union was formed in March 2021 and certified by the National Labor Relations Board in September 2021. In 2022, the CWA, District 1 and the Bird Union launched a campaign to reinstate workers healthcare. In early 2023, the union changed its name to disavow John James Audubon, who was an enslaver and racist and called for the organization to change its name as well.